We're out here today using G-Ratt's new
Magnum Q Bomb.
If you guys are into throwing urchin
baits, [music]
this might be a good video for you to
watch.
Oh, it's a giant. Oh, that's a giant.
That's a giant.
>> [music]
>> On the G-Ratt Magnum Q Bomb.
Come here. Come on, you got
>> [music]
>> Oh.
>> Pop
is gone, boys and girls.
>> [music]
[music]
>> So, I'm excited to be showing you guys
G-Ratt's new Magnum Q Bomb today.
If you guys like throwing urchin baits,
you guys like throwing really big baits
for big bass, you're going to want to
check out G-Ratt's Magnum Q Bomb.
We're out here on the water today with
it. Let's go see if we can catch some
big bass, and at the end of this video,
I'm going to include
a little video that I shot in my garage
of how I make
my
urchin hooks. That's right.
I make them out of a frog hook. There's
a nail weight in there.
And how I get it all together and how I
make it.
So you guys stay tuned to the video.
We're going to fish for a little bit.
We're going to talk about the G-Crak
Magnum Q Bomb. And then at the end of
the video,
a little bit of bonus footage, how to
make
the urchin hook that I use
on these larger
urchin style baits.
So you guys stay tuned.
Q Bombs, they cast like an absolute
dream.
Got one.
First cast.
It's a nice one, guys.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, there we go.
On the G-Crak Magnum Q Bomb, boys.
First cast over a brush pile.
That's on
that frog hook that I make myself.
Well, I don't make the hook, but that's
how I rig it up.
And it works really well because the
bait slides up the line
and the frog hooks just stay pinned in
the fish's mouth.
Black and blue tipped
G-Crak Mag Q Bomb.
This is what I'm talking about.
Get her back in the water.
There she goes.
All right.
Simply just slide our bait back onto the
frog hook here.
Like so.
All right, guys. Well, let's talk about
the G-ratt
Magnum Q-Bomb.
I've been fortunate enough to have my
hands on a few of these over the last
couple of months before the official
release date.
And guys, I got to tell you, I'm nothing
but impressed with this bait. I've
caught a ton of giant fish on Lake Toho
with it.
It's probably because of the size. This
is a big bait, guys.
The diameter of the ball itself is 1 and
1/2 in, so you're right at 30 mm.
The overall diameter of the outside of
this thing is 130 mm.
This thing in the water
attracts a lot of fish. You get a lot of
followers.
And you catch a lot of bigger fish on
this bait. My favorite things about this
bait is the construction.
It's made out of really thick TPE
elastomer material,
which allows it to be very tough and
resilient to damage. It also allows me
to throw a big hook in there. And you
guys saw the one that I caught.
The bait slid up the line like it's
supposed to,
where I only had just my hook stuck in
that fish.
Now, I throw frog hooks on this
that I customize.
That footage is at the end of this video
on how to make the urchin style bait
hook that I use.
I like to throw these baits
around brush piles.
The problem with using a large treble
hook on an urchin style bait around
brush piles is sometimes some days
you've got to get your bait in and
around the pile.
The fish aren't as willing to come out
for it. And when that happens, a lot of
times you get hung up
and we don't always get them back.
To go with a different hooking method,
which is using
large frog hooks that I customize with a
nail weight as well as some tough heat
shrink type material.
Hook up ratios are better
and I'm able to use heavier duty gear.
Like you guys saw in the video, I'm
throwing these baits on a 7-3 medium
heavy Fitzgerald rod,
20-lb fluorocarbon line,
and a 8:1 gear ratio reel. When it comes
to dealing with larger fish,
bigger Florida strain bass, sometimes
finesse is not the best approach if you
have hopes of getting them back to the
boat. And I do not like the treble hook
method.
The treble hook method on baits
seems to lose a lot of fish. So, I like
going
with frog hooks.
Same thing. This is G-Crack Magnum
Q-Bomb, different color.
Both of these colors are in their tipped
color patterns. This is a green pumpkin
chartreuse tip.
And I really like the way G-Crack has
came up with a little bit more of an
innovative design
as opposed to just having
a bunch of tentacles on there.
What it is is it's actually flat pieces
of silicone material that passes through
the body.
And they always
stay upright. They're always They never
get deformed.
You know, other urchin style baits, if
you've used any of them, guys, and I'm
assuming if you're watching this video,
it's because
maybe you are
an urchin bait lover.
The way that G-Crack has manufactured
this bait
with the use of the silicone skirt
material that passes through the body,
the legs never come They never become
deformed.
Other urchin-style baits, after a while,
the tentacles begin to get this like
droop to them, especially if you don't
store them right.
Because of the way G Crack manufactures
the Magnum Cubomb, storage is no longer
an issue. You can throw these baits into
a bag
with other baits
and they don't become deformed.
Noth- It just doesn't seem to mess them
up. This is out of the bag. They've been
in the front box
and they come out
the way they're supposed to.
Really cool color here. I think this is
bluegill orange tip.
The size of the nail weight,
you can alter versus how deep you're
fishing.
Because we're in Central Florida and we
don't fish really deep here, I go pretty
light and these are actually a lead nail
weight.
I believe these to be a 1/16 oz. I could
be wrong. I just kind of go based off of
feel, guys. I'm not really like I don't
get super technical about that kind of
stuff. You know, I don't know. You just
got to feel it out.
But, that's a small lead nail weight
heat shrunk into that hook. Got some
footage in this video on how I make
them.
For big bass, the G Crack Magnum Cubomb,
cast like a rocket, extremely buoyant,
very tough and resilient to damage. You
like throwing a bigger bait, you like
targeting bigger fish,
G Crack Magnum Cubomb.
Lakeland Fishing Outfitters should have
them.
If they don't, they're coming soon.
So, if you were in Central Florida area
you want to get your hands on some
G-Crack Magnum Q-Bombs,
make sure you pop into Lakeland Fishing
Outfitters over on Lake Parker.
We'll catch you guys on the next one.
Like I said earlier, make sure you guys
stay tuned. I'm going to drop in how to
make an urchin style bait hook right
now. The first thing to do is to take
butt splice connector,
the weatherproof ones cuz they shrink
and they've got like a little bit of
glue in them.
You can use
heat shrink tubing, but that's just a
little too soft.
Weatherproof butt splice, I'm going to
take pair of lineman's lineman's pliers,
and I'm going to crimp that
the wire crimp in the middle.
All the way up and down that thing.
There it goes.
Just going to push
this over the hook.
Like so.
The larger frog hook size, you can
basically just use the entire butt
connector. [music]
I'm going to take my nail weight,
I'm going to insert it in here.
And the nail weight will ride ride along
the top of those two hooks.
Cuz it basically acts like a groove for
it to sit on.
It actually sits in there really nicely.
Just like that.
So, now I'm just going to take
my lighter,
apply a little bit of heat to this
weatherproof butt splice.
Another beautiful G-Crack Magnum Q-Bomb.
They've got little [music] through holes
already in them.
Going to take our
hook here that we've just made.
Going to insert it through there.
Beautiful.
There you have it, guys. That
is my
go-to large urchin bait
hook.
Super easy to make in the garage.
Some butt splices.
Crimp up the little metal connector
piece in the middle so it falls out.
Slide it over your hook.
Slide your little nail weight in there.
Heat it up and you're good to go.
>> [music]
[music]